So, when you're creating your composables, you need to make sure that their arguments are flexible,
but they have a standardized return.
What do I mean by that?
We had a chat earlier about how FlutterTast really, when you're looking at this,
it doesn't look particularly like, in fact, we don't see anything imported by view at all here.
The problem is, when I mentioned flexible arguments,
is that, remember, when we're calling these in our components,
filter tasks, let's see, where is FlutterTast being called?
We have an example.
In this particular case, it's actually passing, like, a task object,
but what if, like, task, like, a new task store,
was, like, a ref of tasks?
In this particular case, you're actually going to get an error,
because what you told JavaScript is that I'm passing you an array of tasks.
But at this point, it's technically not an array of tasks.
It's a ref that contains an array of tasks.
And then, oh, yes, I'm seeing some.
I'm going to let you see for that for a second.
Would you, would that be correct if you passed any value of the ref?
Correct. If we did it like this, now it's solved.
But this is why the recommendation here is to be flexible about it.
It's because you can't really guarantee how your developers want to use it.
And it'll always feel a little clunky.
And so, view thought about this.
You know, we see that people are going through this.
How might we solve this? Well, it's actually kind of clever.
So, we have, we have here, we said that it's a type of task,
but we also know it might be a ref.
So, in view, we have this type called maybe ref.
And so, you say, maybe if it's a ref, maybe it's not,
or maybe it's a plain value.
One of the two.
We don't know if it's reactive, but either way, we're going to find a way to deal with it.
And I explain that in a second.
Because, okay, so now you're wondering, right?
Okay, so what does this mean, right?
It could be reactive, meaning it's a ref, meaning it has be unpackaged,
or it's a plain value, and then dot value would not work because it's already a plain value.
And so, this is where the standardizing what you return is important,
because then you, as the composable author, need to decide,
in the rest of this composable.
Do I want this parameter to be a flat value,
or do I need it to be reactive?
If you need it to be a plain value,
there is a helper method from view called two value.
And it'll basically, so basically, we would say, for example,
I'll just say task, let's make it easy in this case,
two value on task list.
So, always forces an unwrap value.
What's next about this is the two value helper function.
If it's not a ref, it'll just spit back the value.
If it is a ref, it will unpack it, and then make it plain.
Your alternative, as if you're, some of you might have guessed,
is to simply wrap it in a ref.
And if you wrap a ref in a ref, it just flattens to a ref.
It's not like you're doing additional performance overhead.
And so, this is where consistency.
In other words, you don't enforce consistency at the parameter level,
where, again, especially with call signatures.
You just don't know what developers are going to try to call it.
So you say, cool, as long as you give me a array of tasks,
whatever it's method, I will then deal with it.
I will standardize it, and I will follow through.
And so, to finish with that particular line of thought,
this also means that whatever you're doing,
you should then probably be consistent about whether you're,
usually returning a reactive value, or you returning a plain value.
Because that is another choice then you have to make as the author.
Because is this something that, and so, one would probably make the case
that if it's a composable, generally you want a reactive value
because it's probably dealing with state.
And so, you want someone to be able to like subscribe to it, watch to it, et cetera.
Whereas, like, you know, if you were doing more like a utility function,
maybe logic, then a plain value is probably the route to go.
But again, to be very clear, that is up to your digression as an author
of whatever composable utility function you should choose to do.
But the key here is flexible arguments standardize like execution within it.
So that they go to hand-in-hand.
And so, I do have to wrap this up with one additional caveat,
and I promise it's just the one more thing.
So, I mentioned that you have regular tasks.
You have the regular value, which in this case is task array,
and you have your rough value.
But, there's also, you can also technically get values from a function.
And so, in this particular case, you can imagine it,
I think this is the signature.
Return task order is a function that returns a task, an array of tasks.
And so, if you put return task stored in here,
this is also going to air out, because it is not a plain value.
It is not a ref. In fact, it is a function.
So, we also call it a geter, because it's getting the value.
So, the reason I want to say this all in one breath,
because I don't want people to get too far ahead of me here,
or it's just runaway and start doing stuff.
Maybe ref is fine, but in reality, what you want,
is maybe ref or geter.
And that completes the evolution of your maybe ref, maybe geter,
maybe plain value.
And with this type, you have, like, essentially,
the a perfectly typed, flexible parameter.
That can be used in whatever context, whatever,
someone wants to call something, because they decided to put a function inside of your
method called whatever, your covered.
And as long as you do your part in the next two pieces,
whether it's flat knit or make it reactive, you're good, you're good G.
Wouldn't you have to call it if it was a geter?
No, so that's the funny thing. Two value and ref will just do their thing.
So that's the beauty of, like, standardizing it at the very top.
You're like, I'm working with reactive values.
Boom, this what I'm doing.
Or no, just plain value.
I was talking to team.
I really wish we could have called that maybe reactive,
because I feel like that would have been good enough,
but unfortunately, reactive is already a term in view.
So it would technically be misleading, but I feel like that's really what we're saying
is this maybe reactive, but unfortunately, that shift is sealed.
So this is what we get.
Anyhow.
Yeah.
Any questions about this pattern of flexible parameters,
but standardized outputs?
I mean, maybe it's just me, but flexible parameters,
that sounds a bit like a drug looking for a disease state.
Some people just really cool method called,
maybe ref are gathering, so how should we use this?
I think part of it is that we encountered people being inconsistent
with how they were calling this function signature,
and because a lot of times you're using these in components,
people were passing reactive values,
but then they weren't handling it correctly inside of then the method,
because then you, because some of us, like for example,
I tend to defaults a reactive values,
but then if I haven't taken a signature where they're expecting plain
or they, then it just kind of botches the whole thing up.
So rather than having these sort of if else statements,
they came up with these helper functions.
But again, I think if your team doesn't have that problem,
like cool, if you're like every composable is a ref,
like don't pass it anything, but you all can stick to that.
I mean, great.
That's what TypeScript is for, right?
That's fair.
Yeah.
So I guess you could say, you could make the case that this is really
maybe more for library authors than.
I've just been on some code like some teams where like,
you know, your developers halfway across the world,
and they're doing tickets.
And so like if the communication not always there in the standards
aren't as easily enforced, then things like this can help
to reduce friction.
But exactly to your point, if your team is using TypeScript in a way
and is consistent, don't even worry about this.
It's just nice to know that this is an option for you,
I guess, is what I want to.
It's so much honesty of my teaching philosophy is to just give you
tools and like different scenarios where it might be useful,
and then you'll know best when it's time to use it or not.
What does TypeScript tell us on the other side of maybe
Refrigerator?
Yep.
So it's the, basically, for those who don't know,
T is essentially a variable letter, essentially any type.
So yep, essentially says it's maybe Reft of T,
computed Reft T, function of T, or just T itself.
So it's a very elaborate, I think they call it union, right?
I think it's a union type.
Should we also create a parameter in the composable to allow
the user to choose the filter or how to filter?
Are they referring to this one right here?
Because I think this is what's, this task filter.
Oh, are they saying that this should also be a maybe Refrigerator?
If they are, they are correct.
At least, according, if I'm using my pattern that I'm explaining right now,
is this what they're referring to?
Yeah, I think that's what they meant.
Yeah.
Yes.
So to who said that and chat your spot on?
Yeah.
So even more about consistency, don't maybe refrigerator one,
and not maybe refrigerator the other.
Like, all flexible or just be very consistent.
Actually, either ways about consistency.
That's the number one thing.
Consistency is the name of the game.